chelseagreen.com 2019-07-06

# Terms of Use & Privacy | Chelsea Green Publishing

We, at Chelsea Green Publishing, value your patronage and personal privacy. We respect the private nature of the information you provide to us and accept the responsibility of protecting that information. This privacy policy may be changed at any time, and we therefore encourage you to revisit this page periodically. If you want to communicate with us about our Policy, please e-mail us at [web@chelseagreen.com](mailto:web@chelseagreen.com).

Chelsea Green Publishing will never sell or rent your information to third parties. The email address you provide to Chelsea Green Publishing may be used by Chelsea Green Publishing for any reason including, but not limited to, editorial purposes, site communication, and notification of changes to our site. _**We will not sell or rent your email address to anyone for any reason**_. At times it is necessary for Chelsea Green Publishing to furnish your personal information to our third party service partners, such as when conducting an e-commerce transaction or sending our e-newsletters.

We collect the e-mail addresses of registered users, but this information is used solely for the purpose of our e-mail newsletters and shopping reminders, and for no other mailings. To remove your e-mail address from the newsletter subscriber list, please send an email to [web@chelseagreen.com](mailto:web@chelseagreen.com)

## Security

Information that we collect is stored on secure servers using standard security procedures and practices appropriate to the nature of the information in an effort to protect information from unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification, or disclosure.

To protect you and your personal account information, Chelsea Green employs SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) technology. SSL is the industry standard and the best software available for secure commerce transactions. We have taken every reasonable precaution to store the data that is collected in a secure manner.

During an online order, it is necessary for Chelsea Green Publishing to send your name, address, telephone number, and credit information to Authorize.net for payment processing. This transaction is conducted securely and in accordance with Authorize.net’s specified procedures. The information we send to Authorize.net is protected by Authorize.net’s own privacy policy. Under no circumstances, will Authorize.net share your information with any third-party. Please review their policy here: [http://www.authorize.net/company/privacy/](https://www.authorize.net/company/privacy/)

We use MailChimp to send out our various newsletters. If you are subscribed to a newsletter, you will always be given the opportunity to unsubscribe immediately and you will not receive any newsletters from that point forward. Under no circumstances will Chelsea Green or Mailchimp share your personal information with any third-party. Please review their privacy policy here: <https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy>

Non-personally identifiable information (as identified above) may be shared with our advertisers or marketing partners. Your personally identifiable information will never be shared with them.

## Automatic Data Collection

When you visit our website, we may collect certain information automatically from your device. The information we collect automatically may include, but is not limited to, information like your IP address, device type, unique device identification numbers, browser-type (such as Firefox, Safari, or Internet Explorer), your Internet Service Provider (ISP), your operating system and carrier. For website users, details of any referring website or exit pages as well as broad geographic location (e.g., country or city-level location) may also be collected.

We may also collect other technical information such as how your device has interacted with our website, including the pages accessed and links clicked, for example, trips viewed and the time and date of these. We may also use this automatic information to prevent and detect fraud. The information does not contain the visitor’s name or e-mail address since the visitor’s browser does not provide this information to the web server.

Collecting this information enables us to better understand the visitors who come to our website, where they come from, and what content on our website is of interest to them. We use this information for our internal analytics purposes and to improve the quality and relevance of our website for our visitors. Information is used to allocate resources effectively and improve the content of our site.

## Voluntary Registration

Certain sections of Chelsea Green Publishing require that visitors register by providing an e-mail address that is recorded in databases on our server. We consider the following, among other things, to be personally identifiable information: first and last name, e-mail address, street address and phone number.

Volunteered information is kept strictly confidential. Chelsea Green Publishing does not share or sell personally identifiable information to other companies. However, information that is voluntarily provided may be used internally. Additionally, Chelsea Green Publishing may choose, on occasion, to include third-party offers in our mailings. We maintain appropriate and reasonable safeguards to ensure the integrity, security, and privacy of the information in our possession.

You may opt not to be included in the e-mail announcements or mailings when you register for one of our offerings. If a particular registration form does not have this option, or, if you’d like to be removed from our lists for any reason, notify Chelsea Green directly by emailing [web@chelseagreen.com](mailto:web@chelseagreen.com). Please include your name, e-mail address so that we can effectively remove you from the database.

## Cookies

A cookie is a small piece of information that a Web server asks your browser to store on the hard drive of your computer. Your browser later presents the information back to the Web server. In its simplest form, a cookie is just an identifying number. A number of functions on the website do use cookies to enable certain features.

This website may use cookies for the following general purposes, including but not limited to:

  * To help us recognize you as a previous visitor and save and remember any preferences that may have been set while your browser was visiting our site.
  * To help measure and research the effectiveness of website features, offerings and email communications (by determining which emails you open and act upon).

The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to request to disable cookies. Please note that if you refuse to accept cookies, you may not be able to access some of the tools and special offers offered on our site.

## Links to Other Sites

This site may be linked to sites that are not operated by Chelsea Green Publishing or any company affiliated with Chelsea Green Publishing. Chelsea Green Publishing is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of these third party sites. This site may also be linked to Web sites operated by companies affiliated with Chelsea Green Publishing. Visitors to those sites should refer to their separate privacy policies and practices.

## Contests and Promotions

Chelsea Green Publishing may run contests and promotions on our sites that may require the submission of personal information by participants. Chelsea Green Publishing may use the information collected during a contest for research purposes, for example, to determine how many visitors participated in the contest.

## Copyright

Copyright © 2019 Chelsea Green. All rights reserved. No material herein may be reproduced in any form by any means without the express written consent of Chelsea Green Publishing.

## Request the removal of your data from Chelsea Green Publishing servers

If you are a Chelsea Green Publishing customer or end-user and would like to have your data fully removed from our servers please fill out the form below.
